Guide to the Samuel King Allison Papers 1920-1965
University of Chicago Library
Allison, Samuel King. Papers
1920-1965
19.5 linear feet (41 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Samuel King Allison (1900-1965), physicist. The papers document his career at the University of Chicago, both as student and faculty member, and his research on X-rays and lithium. The papers also include material on his service as director of the Enrico Fermi Institute for Nuclear Studies (1945-1965), and his chairmanship of the Physics Section of the National Academy of Sciences. The collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, notebooks, course notes, reprints, lectures, and speeches.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Samuel King Allison was born in Chicago on November 13, 1900. In 1917 he entered the University of Chicago and received his Bachelor of Science degree in 1921 and his doctorate in 1923. Following his graduation, he became a fellow of the National Research Council at Harvard University (1923-1925); a fellow at the Carnegie Institute (1925-1926); and a member of the faculty at the University of California (1926-1930). In 1930 Allison returned to the University of Chicago, and, from that time until his death in September 1965, continued to be associated with the University.
During his career at the University of Chicago, Allison was not only active as a teacher and a research scientist, but also as an administrator and a civil servant. In the 1930s, Allison conducted experiments with X-rays, and published his results in a book, X-rays in Theory and Experiment. In the 1940s he began work on the liberation of nuclear energy, and was a member of the team working under Enrico Fermi which achieved the first self-sustaining nuclear chain reaction on December 2, 1942. Between 1943 and 1944 Allison served as director of the "Metallurgical Laboratory" which was developing a method for producing plutonium.
In November, 1944 Allison joined the Manhattan Project and was chairman of the Technical and Scheduling Committee at the Los Alamos Laboratory. He returned to the University of Chicago in 1945 to become the first director of the newly-formed Enrico Fermi Institute for Nuclear Studies. While director of the Institute, Allison encouraged the exchange of scientific information, free from military control. Allison also helped to found The Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, and visited Spain and South America as guest lecturer and advisor.
In order to devote all of his time to research projects, Allison resigned as director of the Fermi Institute in 1958. He continued to travel, however, and was appointed by the Organization of American States to a "Direct Technical Assistance Field Mission" to the Centro Atomico, San Carlos de Variloche. From 1960 to 1963 Allison also served as Chairman of the Physics Section of the National Academy of Sciences.
When Herbert L. Anderson, Allison's successor at the Fermi Institute, resigned in 1963 to continue his research with a new particle accelerator at Argonne National Laboratory, Allison resumed his duties as director. Two years later, on September 1, 1965, Allison died while attending the Plasma Physics and Controlled Nuclear Fusion Research Conference held in Culham, England.
Scope Note
The Samuel King Allison papers contain 19.5 linear ft. of material that cover the period from the 1920s to the 1960s. The papers document his career at the University of Chicago, both as student and faculty member, and his research on X-rays and lithium. It also includes material on his service as director of the Enrico Fermi Institute for Nuclear Studies (1945-1965), and his chairmanship of the Physics Section of the National Academy of Sciences. The collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, notebooks, course notes, reprints, lectures, and speeches. The files themselves have not been formally processed and reflect the original order of the donation.
The collection has been divided into six series:
Series I contains materials from the University of Chicago.
Series II contains Allison’s X-ray Research.
Series III is Allison’s Lithium Research.
Series IV contains materials from the Enrico Fermi Institute for Nuclear Studies.
Series V contains materials from the National Academy of Sciences.
Series VI contains Allison’s Visual Materials.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Allison, Samuel King, 1900-1965; Enrico Fermi Institute; Manhattan Project (U.S.); University of Chicago. Dept. of Physics; Betatrons; X-rays; Physics
INVENTORY
- Series I: University of Chicago
  - Subseries 1: Notes, Outlines, Lectures for Physics Courses
    - General file, departmental courses, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Physics 326, Spring 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Physics 262-263, Winter and Spring 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Physics 242, Summer 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Physics 211, Spring 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Physics 105 & 106 & 107, 1948 and 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Physics 463, Theory of Collisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Nuclear Physics 262 & 263, Winter & Spring 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Basic, 1951 (Jan. - S.K.A. on committee), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Physics 362, Fall 1952, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Physics 362, Spring 1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Physics 102, Winter 1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Physics 215, Autumn, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Physics 237, Spring 1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Physics 121, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Spring 1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Physics 121, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Physics 362, Autumn 1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Physics 223, Spring 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Physics 237, Spring 1963 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Physics 235, Autumn 1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Placement Exam, Autumn 1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Physics 235, Autumn 1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Department of Physics, PhD Candidacy Exams, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: S. K. Allison's Physics Notebooks
    - Physics 105, 106, 107 (1948) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Physics 211, Mechanics, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Line Spectra, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "153 Problems in Differential Equations from Murray's Text," S. K. Allison, Math 47, Autumn Quarter, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Notes: Physics 11 First Term," undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "Electricity and Magnetism" (Filed September, 1954), undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Sophomore Physics, Mechanics, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Sophomore Physics, Sound and Heat, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Alpha Particles, Counting Analyses, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Solutions to Electro Chemistry Problems, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Theoretical Physics, Part One, Electricity and Magnetism, Fall Quarter, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Notes on Theory of Definite Integrals and Fourier Series, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Solved Problems, Spring 1921 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Physics 361, X-Rays: "Scattering from Gases, i.e. the Dispersion," undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Original X-Ray lectures, 1931-1932: Maxwell's Equations, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Physics 254, "Elect - Mag.," undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Physics 356, Atomic Spectra & Atomic Structure, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Thermodynamics (1920) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Electron (1920) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Electricity and Magnetism" (1929) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Electron Theory Book I (1922) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Electron Theory Book II (1922) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Number 1: Notes on Electromagnetic Theory of Light (Kimble's Lectures), undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Number 2: (Contents listed on outside of notebook) (1925) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Number 3: (Contents listed on outside of notebook), undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Number 4: (Contents listed on outside of notebook), undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Number 5: (Contents listed on outside of notebook), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Atommechanik," undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Physics 357, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Physics 362, Fall 1961 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Stopping Theory, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Nuclear Physics Lectures, IV (Contents listed), undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Stopping Power, Kevatron Research, current, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Nuclear Physics Lecture I, Contents listed on outside cover, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Nuclear Physics Lecture II, Contents listed on outside cover, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Nuclear Physics Lecture III, Contents listed on outside cover, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Lecture material A, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Lectures material B, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Thick target scattering, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Physics 235
    - Lecture notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Exams, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Homework, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous material, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Laboratory, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Student records, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 4: Miscellaneous Notes and Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1945-1963 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 20th Anniversary of Chain Reaction, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Physics department, 1945-1949 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Physics College, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Series II: X-ray Research
  - Apparatus, Accelerating Tubes, undated Counting Circuits, undated Cloud Chambers, undated Miscellaneous, undated Vacuum Spectrometers, undated Photographic Spectrometers, undated Resistances, undated Insulators, undated Oils, undated Transformers, undated Vacuum, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Angular Distribution, Angular Distribution, undated Applications to Life Science, undated Radio-Hydrogen, Carbon, Nitrogen, undated Radio-Oxygen, Sodium, undated Radio-Phosphorus, undated Radio-Sulfur, Chlorine, Bromine, Iodine, undated Radio-Potassium, Calcium, Strontium, undated Radio-Iron, undated Other radioactive substances, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Application to Medical Sciences, Radio-Hydrogen, Carbon, Nitrogen, undated Radio-Sodium, undated Radio-Phosphorus, Lukemia, undated Radio-Phosphorus, miscellaneous, undated Radio-Sulfur, Halogens, undated Radio-Potassium, Calcium, undated Radio-Iron, undated Neutrons, undated Other radio-active substances, undated Miscellaneous, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Artificial Radioactivity, By alpha particles, undated By deuterons, undated By protons, undated General, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Beta Ray Spectra, Heavy elements, undated Light elements, undated Neutrinos, undated Theory, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Constitution of nuclei, Nuclear forces, undated Nuclear levels, n.d Magnetic moments, n.d Nuclear particles, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Cosmic rays, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Cyclotron, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Fission, Absorption of, undated Experiment, undated Theory, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Gamma rays, Excitation of, undated Internal conversion, undated Origin of, undated Widths of levels, undated Selection of rules, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - High potential sources, Van de Graaf, undated Cockroft Wallon, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Institutional reports, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Ion sources, Ion sources, undated Ion sources, undated Installation, undated Theory, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Detection, Of gamma rays, undated Of particles, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Disintegration, By alpha particles, undated By deutrons, undated By electrons, undated Energies of, undated Excitation of, undated Natural disintegrations, undated By neutrons, undated By protons, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "The X-Ray K Spectra of Some Heavy Elements," by David Saxon, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - X-Rays, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Isomerism, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Isotopes, 0 Z 30, undated 30 Z 60, undated 60 Z, undated Distribution of, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Masses, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Mesotrons, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Neutrons, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Orbital electron capture, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Pair emission, Experiment, undated Theory, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Photodisintegration, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Radio Chemistry, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Ranges, Of alpha particles, undated Of deutrons and protons, undated Of electrons and positrons, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Scattering, Of alpha particles, undated Neutrons - proton, undated Proton - proton, undated Of electrons, undated Of other particles, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Statistics, Of radioactive decay, undated Of counting circuits, undated Of nuclei, undated Other particles, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - "Focussing of Spheres", undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Stellar energies, undated, Star evolution, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Summarizing articles, undated, High voltage power supply, undated Ranges of particles, undated D-D reaction, undated Energy selection by modulation, undated Mass life and various materials,, undated Protection from collimation, undated Efficiency of - production of, undated Velocity selection, undated Scattering, undated Slowing down of, undated Reaction induced by, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Neutrons in fission, undated, High energy, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Neutrons - high energy, undated, Scattering of, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Neutrons - resonance, undated, Capture, theory, undated Capture, experiment, undated Weather of levels, undated Scattering of, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Neutrons - thermal, undated, Absorption, experiment, undated Absorption, theory, undated Diffusion, experiment, undated Disintegration produced by --, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Neutrons, general, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Series III: Lithium Research
  - Nineteen envelopes containing, for the most part, experimental data on lithium, undated (Box 22)
  - Seven envelopes containing experimental data on lithium, undated (Box 23)
- Series IV: Enrico Fermi Institute for Nuclear Studies
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence, Articles, and Speeches
    - Allison `Diary' concerning bomb tests at Alamogordo, New Mexico, July 16, 1945; Article for Science, November 16, 1962, about Arthur H. Compton. Reprint and letters, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Trustees Dinner, January 1960, Speech and Correspondence (University of Chicago), 1960 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Article for Bulletin of Atomic Scientists, December 1962, "Thoughts on the 20th Anniversary of the First Chain Reaction." Correspondence and article (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Twentieth Anniversary of the First Chain Reaction Luncheon, December 1, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - I.A.E.A. Bulletin, December 1962 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Comments on basic research for NAS, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Speech for National Association of Physical Plant Administration, May 1963 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Reprints (duplicates) of Allison's articles, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - "Science and Government" delivered for the University College, ca. 1958 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - "Science and Scientists as National Assets" delivered at Chicago Teachers Union, April 19, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - "Science and Scientists" delivered at Monsanto Science Club, St. Louis, September 23, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - "Phi Beta Kappa," Chicago, June 10, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - "The Moon, Sputniks, Sewer Pipes and Atoms," Navy Pier, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Allison's memoirs of A. H. Compton, manuscript and reprint, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - H. A. Bethe, Honorary Degree presented by SKA, Convocation, June 12, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Book reviews, undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Enrico Fermi file, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - "On the Hydrogen Bomb," 1950 and 1956 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Reprint of article "Uranium and the Shape of Things to Come," appeared in Confluence, April 1956 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - E. P. Winger Honorary Degree, December 20, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - "Survival of the fittest: Race for Space," undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - American Society for Metals dinner, November 1957 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - "Thoughts on the Tenth Anniversary of First Chain Reaction," article which appeared in the University of Chicago Magazine, December 1952 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Alumni lecture, December 18, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - A. H. Compton Honorary degree, December 18, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - "Comments on Universities in U.S.," (Reply to Leopold Infeld), April 23, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Hamburg Conference on Cultural Freedom, July 24-25, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Symposium on Intellectual Freedom and the Elections, October 29, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Research Corporation Dinner (Libby Award), ca. March 18, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - "Responsibilities of a University Professor," Puerto Rico, March 15, 1951 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Experimental Program of Institute for Nuclear Studies, Mexico, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - "The State of Physics or the Perils of Being Important," November 26, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Reprints of articles: "Control and Beneficial Use of Atoms"; "Atomic Energy in Industry and the Physical Sciences"; "Institute for Nuclear Studies,", undated (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, Advisory Council (Science) of the Democratic National Committee, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous correspondencev (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Assorted old publications, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - MPE, Report and meeting, November 20, 1953 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Pare Lorentz film "No Place to Hide," script, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - "Condon and Shortley,", undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Argonne Midwest Accelerator, file inactive since 1957 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Brookhaven Visiting Committee, file inactive since 1959 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Letters on x-ray book to Van Norstrand Co., Inc. and letters from A. H. Compton about book, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Books: Abridged edition of B. O. Pierce's "A Short Table of Integrals"; Second revised edition of "A Short Table of Integrals"; Fourth edition of Barlow's Tables, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Reprints of articles, undated (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, Penetration of Charged Particles, 1956-1957 (Box 29)
    - Oak Ridge Reports, 1956-1958 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1945-1963 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1945-1963 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1945-1963 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Louis Slotin, personal history, 1945-1948 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Slotin Memorial Fund, 1947-1960 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: Betatron Files
    - Betatron equipment, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Betatron equipment, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Betatron budget estimates, undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Betatron, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Betatron, "Donut", undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - G. E. Conference, January 23-24, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Betatron, technical file, 1949-1950 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Betatron, operating rules, proposed, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Betatron, magnet, undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Monthly statements of expenditures and encumbrances for 100 mev. betatron, 1949-1950, 1950-1951, 1951-1952 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Betatron, financial statements and finances, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Betatron, health physics, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Betatron, letters to G. E., undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Betatron, contracts, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Betatron pole change, undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Betatron, letters to G. E., Chicago Office, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Various, undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Various, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 3: Notes, Memoranda, and Correspondence, undated
    - Institute, Nuclear Physics Journal Club, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Institute, housing, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Crank letters, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Allison, engagements, 1949-1950 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Allison, engagements, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Allison, engagements, miscellaneous, undated (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Atomic power letters, undated (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Atomic Scientists of Chicago, undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Bush - Groves - Hutchins, undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Franck, undated (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Ford Foundation (C. S. Smith to C. C. Lauritsen), undated (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Libby, undated (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - MGM movie, undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Mulliken, undated (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Press releases, undated (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Flugge article, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Allison, personal correspondence, aid to California, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Allison, personal correspondence, lure, visa situation, undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Institute, miscellaneous, undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Purchase orders, 1948-1955 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - (3 in 1) travel expenses, undated (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 4: Correspondence
    - General correspondence, ca. 1953-1955; Engagement calendar, 1956-1957 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Personal correspondence before 1955, McCarrau Act, undated Rosenberg case, undated Britannica article, undated Hydrogen bomb, undated Condon case, undated Clearance laws and Loyalty Board, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding Controlled Thermonuclear Fusion Panel, 1965 (Box 35, Folder 3)
- Series V: National Academy of Sciences
  - Allison's trip to Egypt in 1960, January through March, under the auspices of the Department of State, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Allison's trip to Egypt in 1960, January through March, under the auspices of the Department of State, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Allison's trip to Argentina, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - American Institute of Physics, Visiting Scientists Program, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Physics, Teaching of, undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1964 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Atomic Energy Bills, printed copies, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 2)
- Series VI: Visual Materials
  - 95 Plastic and glass lantern slides of charts, graphs, drawings, and photographs of nuclear research equipment, used for lectures and seminars (FRAGILE), circa 1970s (Box 38)
  - 88 Plastic and glass lantern slides of charts, graphs, drawings, and photographs of nuclear research equipment, used for lectures and seminars (FRAGILE), circa 1970s (Box 39)
  - 45 Plastic and glass lantern slides of charts, graphs, drawings, and photographs of nuclear research equipment, used for lectures and seminars (FRAGILE), circa 1970s (Box 40)
  - 77 Plastic 35mm slides of charts, graphs, drawings, and photographs of nuclear research equipment, used for lectures and seminars (FRAGILE), undated (Box 41)